Muhammad Nasser Muhammad

Flutter Developer

💌 memonasser135@gmail.com 📞 (+2) -01284371026 👂 17 El Abd 1200, El Salam city, Cairo, Egypt

21/12/2000 **in** LinkedIn **(7)** Github

PROFILE

I'm a Self-motivated Developer with high level of experience over more than 2 years collaborating and working on multiple mobile app-based projects. Passionate, hardworking coder with penchant for developing customized interfaces that factor in unique demands for accessibility, reachability, and security. Organized approach to meeting multiple, concurrent deadlines. Pulls from active knowledge of current technology landscape to promote best practices in mobile app development.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Flutter Developer

Freelance

07/2022 - present Cairo, Egypt

- Designed, developed, tested, and implemented mobile apps based on analyzed clients' requirements and understanding of industry technical standards.
- Samples of apps:

1- Furnitured:

Furniture e-commerce app with the best experience and user experience and inspiring interface.

2- food delivery app:

This application is for a restaurant that delivers food to users, with better user experience by getting detailed food info and easy payment.

Music app with one of the best UI designs and user experience and available for online and offline usage.

Flutter Developer

Hossam-X-Studios ≥

07/2023 - 01/2024 Cairo, Egypt

- Designed, developed, and implemented mobile applications based on analyzed requirements and understanding of industry technical standards.
- Responsibility for publishing apps on Google play and App Store.
- Samples of Apps:

1- **Ask-Bank** (Quizzes Game):

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hossam_x_studios.ask_bank

2- Zone-User:

Multi-vendor e-commerce for Zone company where users can browse and order products, services from shops.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hossam_x_studios.zoneApp &

3- Zone-Shops:

shops app for Zone by which the user can edit his products.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hossam_x_studios.zoneShop

4- Zone-Vendor:

vendors app for Zone by which the vendor can add, edit, delete products or shops. https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.Hossam_x_studios.vendorapp

5- Zone-delivery:

delivery app for zone by which the delivery man can accept and deliver products from the shop to the user.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?

id=com.Hossam_x_studios.zoneDelivery &

Flutter Developer

Smart Gate IT &

02/2024 – present Cairo, Egypt

- Responsibility for designing, developing, and implementing mobile applications based on analyzed requirements and understanding of industry technical standards
- Responsibility for publishing apps on Google play and App Store.
- Samples of Apps:

1- Resticho:

A Collection of 6 Apps to handle Restaurant systems.

(Customer - Cashier - Sub cashier - Waiter - Kitchen - Notifier).

2-Cascade:

Banking App used for requesting loans and credits from governmental banks in Saudi Arabia.

3-Tennis Home:

Tennis, Yoga, Padel Courts Renting Systems that consists of two apps. (Business - Business) and (Business - Customer)

SKILLS

- Proficiency in dealing with RESTful APIs.
- Ability to integrate Firebase, FCM, Payments, Web sockets, and Google Maps and ads services.
- Proficiency in version control (GitHub).
- Data Structures, Algorithms, and Strong analytical and problem-solving skills.
- Ability to quickly adapt to new technologies.
- Familiarity with Agile development.
- Proficiency in dealing with Figma and Adobe XD UI/UX designs.
- SOLID Principles.
- Familiar with MVVM, MVC and Clean Architecture.

LANGUAGES

Arabic

• • • • •

English

 \bullet \bullet \bullet

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree of Computer and Systems Engineering.

Faculty of Engineering Ainshams university ≥

Year: 4th Computers and Systems Engineering

GPA: 2.35 (Very Good)

Expected Graduation Year: 2024

09/2019 – present Cairo, Egypt

COURSES

Flutter & Dart Complete Development Course [2023] @

Eng./ Tharwat Samy

Flutter Advanced Course Bloc and MVVM Pattern [Arabic][2023] @

Eng./ Tharwat Samy

Deep Dive into Clean Architecture in Flutter[Arabic] @

Eng./ Tharwat Samy

Mastering Flutter: Responsive & Adaptive UI Design [Arabic] ∂